(JOSH SNORING)
(CREAKING)
Mom?
Hey. sweetie.
What are you doing up?
Come here.
I don't like my room.
No?
That's okay.
You know. you're still
getting used to it.
I can't sleep either.
What are you
looking at?
Some old photos.
You want to see?
Do you know
who that is?
No.
It's me.
It doesn't
look like you.
(LAUGHS)
I know.
But that's me.
That's your mom.
I was a kid once. too.
believe it or not.
You're old now.
How old do you
think I am?
Really old.
Oh.
Have a guess.
Probably at least. uh. 21.
(SIGHS) I wish
you were right.
Show me a picture
of when Dad
was a little kid.
You know.
I wish I could.
But I don't think
we have any.
He's really hopeless
at keeping photos.
Show me
a picture of when
I was a little kid.
You are a little kid.
You're wonderful.
(CALI CRYING)
You certainly
didn't cry as much
as your little sister.
But she's up.
so let's go.
Get some breakfast.
Billing department.
Let me play.
No.
I want to play!
I'm eating breakfast!
Billing department. Careful.
FOSTER: I need
a bowl. Mom.
I don't want to play soon.
I want to play now.
DALTON: No. no. no. no.
Here. here.
It's too small.
Well.
just make it work.
Speak to an agent.
(CALI CRYING)
Oh. man. what?
Every time I think
I've pulled you out.
(GRUNTS) you grow back in.
God.
Good morning. guys.
Speak to an agent!
I'm an agent.
Yeah. hello.
I would really like
to keep the old number
if that's possible.
Dude. don't eat
on the floor. Foster.
But I'm pouring my cereal.
Can I have it
by the end of the day.
please. because I...
Yes. Okay. Thank you.
Foster.
can you please
get up off the floor?
Cap's loose.
What is this?
Is that wax?
We have no actual fruit?
We have wax fruit?
God damn it.
And. honey.
if you wanna
look at my books.
please don't leave them
all over the floor.
I didn't
touch your books.
Bye.
See you. Dad.
See you. buddy.
You're not
gonna take the
boys to school?
I can't today. Bye.
Are you gonna
pick them up?
I can't.
I got a PTA meeting.
I totally forgot.
Why didn't you tell me?
I'm sorry.
Oh. no. no. no.
don't cry. Don't cry.
I'll see you guys. Bye.
(RENAI PLAYING PIANO)
RENAI:
♪ Yeah. I'm looking west
♪ Always been looking that way
♪ I'm gonna get
it all happening
♪ Just can't do it today
♪ Yeah. I'm looking west
♪ Always been looking that way
♪ I'm gonna be somebody
♪ I just can't be her today ♪
(CALI CRYING
OVER BABY MONITOR)
(CRYING)
It's okay.
(CREAKING NOISE)
(LADDER RUNG BREAKS)
(SIGHS)
JOSH: Hello?
Daddy!
Hey. buddy. slow down...
Whoa! This is awesome!
Share it with your brother.
Okay.
Share with your brother.
Come watch TV with me.
All right.
Look at this. babe.
Nice job!
Yes. it's getting there.
Getting there?
It looks awesome.
Thanks.
Hey.
Hi.
(GRUNTING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Have you seen
my box of sheet
music anywhere?
Uh. I don't know. babe.
I know we packed them.
I packed them.
I know. I just...
I can't find them.
I think the movers
might have put them
in the dining room.
Come here.
baby girl. come here.
It's not in
the dining room.
I've unpacked
every single box.
and it's just vanished.
I can't find it.
We'll find them.
(GRUNTS)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(COOING)
(CREAKING)
(DALTON SCREAMING)
Dalton. honey?
Where are you?
Stay here. Foster.
stay with your sister.
Dalton?
JOSH: Dalton!
Dalton!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
RENAI: Hey!
JOSH: What?
Hey. hey. Hey.
(STOPS SCREAMING)
What happened?
Did you fall?
Did you fall off the ladder?
Honey. did you fall down?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
What are you doing
climbing the ladder?
Honey...
Sorry. Sorry.
Are you okay?
What hurts? What hurts?
My leg.
All right. Can you move it?
Can you move your leg?
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh. man.
What happened to your head?
Oh. gosh!
Scraped it.
Okay. (PANTING)
Honey. you cannot
come up here. okay?
Do not explore anymore.
It's very dangerous. okay?
It's off limits now.
I'm sorry. Mom.
Okay. Okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Can you stand on it?
Be careful.
I think so.
I got you. Come here.
What are you doing?
You scared us. buddy.
You were just doing
a little exploring?
DALTON: Yeah.
RENAI: So. no more
exploring up there. okay?
DALTON: Okay.
Yeah. you may be
a superhero. buddy.
but you're not invincible.
You gotta be careful.
all right?
Okay.
Yeah.
Good night. sweetie.
So were you
putting boxes
away upstairs?
Don't. Josh.
I just hate feeling
helpless. Sorry.
I'll figure out
a way to lock
the door tomorrow.
Good.
It's dangerous. you know.
Maybe we should
just put him on
a child leash.
I'll stop at
the pet store tomorrow.
I'm sorry I was pissy
when you got home
from work today.
No. didn't notice.
I was trying
to do some work
today and then
Cali woke up
after a half hour. and...
And she wouldn't
go back down.
and I just didn't
get anything done.
I just want things to be
different in this house.
Mmm.
I just had
such a bad day.
I'm scared nothing
is gonna change.
It will.
I promise you.
We've just got
to give it time.
Thanks for letting me
take some time to
work on my music.
Come on.
I want you to do it.
I think I have
a couple of good songs.
I mean.
not all of them.
but I think...
You know.
there's a few that
I can do something with.
I love all your songs.
Shut up. You do not!
I do. Stop it.
Which one's
your favorite?
Ooh.
(LAUGHS)
You should write
a song about me.
They're all about you.
Like how cool I am.
Like.
"He's the coolest guy..."
No. no. no. no. no.
No. no. no.
Shh. Quiet.
"Big muscles!"
"Really. really pretty!"
Shh. you'll
wake up the baby.
(MUMBLES)
Shh.
Foster. can you finish
your eggs. please?
(CRYING)
Hey. Cali.
Can you go
wake up Dalton. Josh?
Yeah.
Hey.
Mr. Sleepy-pants. Get up.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey. Sleepy-pants.
You'd better get
out of that bed
or your mother's
gonna kill us both.
Dalton. come on. buddy.
You gotta get
ready for school.
Hey. Hey.
Dalton.
Dalton?
Dalton. Dalton.
Dalton. Dalton!
There is no brain damage
that we've detected.
Technically. yes.
he's in a coma.
He doesn't react to stimuli.
He has no sleep-wake cycle.
But there's no brain
trauma or infection.
His scans are all normal.
To be honest.
I've never seen
anything like it.
But he can't
just not wake up.
I mean...
There's got
to be something.
I'm sorry.
Okay. so...
So what do we do?
Does he stay here?
Do we...
We'll conduct
some further testing.
It's only been
a couple of days.
It could take
a little longer for...
(PAGER BEEPING)
Excuse me a minute.
I have to step out.
I'll be back in just a moment.
Dr. Sercarz.
how long will
the tests take?
(ECG BEEPING)
NURSE: Okay. so what
I've done here is
I've inserted
a nasogastric feeding tube.
To get the length
of the tube that
I'm gonna need.
I measure from
the tip of the
nose to the earlobe
and down to the
xiphoid process.
which is here.
Then I usually
mark that off
with some tape.
And then you
need to lubricate
the end of the tube
that I'm
going to insert
about four inches.
And then I just
slide it in like that.
I have to make sure
the end of the tube
is curved
and that his head
is a little bent.
a little bent back.
And then we usually
hold it in place with
some surgical tape.
And that's it.
(VOICE ECHOING)
If there's any problems
or any bleeding.
just call me. okay?
(INDISTINCT)
(PLAYING)
(PLAYS WRONG NOTE)
(STATIC ON BABY MONITOR)
(WHIRLING NOISES)
MALE VOICE:
There's nothing you can do.
Nothing you can do.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING
ON BABY MONITOR)
(CHUCKLING)
I want it!
Give me it!
I want it...
(ROARS) Now!
(CALI CRYING)
Hey. hey. hey.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
What's this?
An award.
That's today's date.
Did you get this today?
Honey.
why didn't you tell us?
I know it's
hard right now.
but things
are going to
get better. I promise.
I'm gonna show
this to your dad.
It's fantastic.
I'm scared. Mom.
Scared of what?
Dalton.
Can I change rooms?
Why would you want
to change rooms?
I don't like
when he walks
around at night.
(BEEPING)
(RADIO STATIC SOUNDING)
(CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
Something really weird
happened to me today.
Huh. What?
I heard
this noise coming
from Cali's room.
It was on
the baby monitor.
It was like voices.
And I ran up here
and I had a look.
but there was
no one in there.
(CHUCKLES)
It was probably
just interference.
Those things are
always picking up
somebody else's signal.
I don't know.
It sounded so clear.
It was like
this whispering.
It was...
It scared the
hell out of me.
I was at the piano.
and I could hear it
on the monitor.
and I turned up
the volume and...
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Who the hell is that?
(BANGING REPEATS)
Hold on.
Stay here.
Who is it?
Jesus.
(SIGHS)
Hello?
(BEEPS)
(CALI WAILING OVER MONITOR)
(CALI CRYING)
Oh. my God!
Josh! Josh! Josh!
Please.
Someone's in Cali's room!
There's someone there!
I saw somebody!
He was standing right there!
There's nobody here.
I saw someone!
(ALARM BLARING)
Okay. okay.
take her. get Foster.
go in Dalton's room.
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
Foster!
What's going on?
The alarm's gone off!
(ALARM STOPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ALARM STARS BLARING)
God damn it!
(ALARM STOPS)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Thanks. guys.
I'll see you tomorrow.
(EXHALES)
Hey. honey.
It's me. Um...
They just told me.
I've got to. uh...
I'm gonna have to
stay late tonight to...
I gotta grade some tests.
and it's gonna be
a while so. um...
You don't have
to wait up. okay?
I'll be home
as soon as I can.
I love you.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
Did he respond to
any of the new tests?
No. No. he didn't.
But we have to
give it time.
I've seen coma patients
with a much longer
inactivity time
suddenly start
making noises.
He's not in a coma.
They don't know
what to call it.
what to do with him.
so they've
just given up.
I feel like
the universe is just
trying to see
how far I'll bend
before I break.
Well. the universe
picked a fight with
the wrong chick.
That's okay.
I got it.
Thank you.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
(PHONE CHIMES)
RENAI: (ON VOICEMAIL)
Josh. where are you?
I need you to come
home now. please.
It's 10:30.
Mmm-hmm.
You've been
coming home late
every single night.
In all the years
you've worked at the school.
you've never
had to do that.
Why all of a sudden
are you staying back late?
You know.
I don't like it either.
I was grading tests.
I mean...
What choice do I have?
I've got to pay
Dalton's bills.
Josh.
I'm scared.
I'm so scared and...
He's my son. too.
You don't understand.
I'm scared for Dalton.
I'm scared
of this house.
There's something
wrong with this place.
I'm not imagining it.
I can feel it.
It's like a sickness.
Ever since we've moved in.
everything's just gone wrong.
You think
our house is haunted?
I don't think it.
I know it.
Things move
around in here
by themselves.
I walk into the kitchen
at night to get a drink.
I can feel eyes on me.
I can't be in there
alone anymore.
I need you.
But you're never here.
Where are you?
I told you.
I was grading tests.
That's not what I mean.
You're not here
with me in this situation.
You're just
avoiding it.
like everything stressful.
whether it's this
or parking tickets.
Oh. God.
Stop saying that. okay?
I don't avoid
stressful situations.
I'm just dealing with it
in my own fucking way.
(SIGHS)
Fine. Deal with this!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CREAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Jesus.
Oh. God.
(FLOOR THUDDING)
Josh?
Josh.
(SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(RENAI SCREAMING)
(CALI CRYING)
Renai?
Renai!
(SCREAMING)
What. what. what?
What is it?
There's someone here.
There's someone
in the room!
He was right there.
I swear!
Don't you dare
not believe me.
(CRYING) Please.
Please. believe me.
I swear
he was right there.
I do. I do.
I do believe you.
I just don't know
what you want me to do.
I want to leave. Please.
I want to leave this house.
I can't spend
another night here. Please!
Please. help me!
Okay. okay. okay.
We're going.
Lorraine. please.
you shouldn't be doing
any of this. Just sit down.
I'm perfectly capable
of putting a few things away.
I did it for Josh
his whole life.
I know.
but I feel terrible.
I think it's you who
should be sitting down
by the looks of it.
I can't believe
you got Josh to
hold still for a photo.
What I can't believe is
that we are doing this
all over again.
Ridiculous.
You must think
I'm crazy.
Nobody.
not me or anybody.
knows what you're
going through right now.
Whatever you have to do
to get through it. do it.
And you don't have to
apologize for anything.
Thanks.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(RECORD SCRATCHING)
(RADIO STATIC SOUNDING)
(TIPTOE THROUGH THE TULIPS
PLAYING)
♪ Tiptoe through the window
♪ By the window.
that is where I'll be
♪ Come tiptoe
through the tulips with me
♪ Tiptoe from the garden
♪ By the garden
of the willow tree
♪ And tiptoe
through the tulips with me ♪
(SONG STOPS)
(DOOR SQUEAKING)
(CHILD LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLING)
(DALTON'S
HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
(CHILD LAUGHING)
Dalton?
(LAUGHING PLAYFULLY)
(CRYING)
Your faith can help.
Trust it. you know.
Hello.
Josh.
This is the first line
of a joke. right?
A guy comes home
to find his wife
with a priest.
Uh. this is
Liam Martin.
Nice to meet you.
He's actually a very
old friend of mine.
This is my husband. Josh.
What's going on here?
I should be going.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you
so much for the tea.
This thing from
the other house
has followed us here.
I saw something today.
I thought it was
a little boy.
I followed it
into Dalton's room.
But it wasn't a child.
It was something else.
So what? You just
brought a priest in
to get rid of it?
I didn't know
what else to do. Josh.
Come on. Renai.
When's the last time
you went to church?
What's happening
to Renai is real.
I've seen it for myself.
I came today
because last night
I had a dream
about this place.
I was in this house.
but it was late at night.
I was afraid.
I went into your bedroom.
but you were both asleep.
I knew
I was asleep
in the dream.
but I could feel
that someone was awake
in the house.
I went
into Dalton's room.
There was something
in there with him.
It was
standing there
in the corner.
I asked it.
"Who are you?"
And it said
it was a visitor.
I said.
"What do you want?"
(CREAKING)
It said. "Dalton."
I can still
hear that voice.
(CREAKING)
(SCREAMS)
What? What?
It's here!
What?
(THUDDING)
(BANGS)
Jesus!
Oh. my God!
JOSH: Okay. He's okay.
Please! Please.
help him! Please!
I know someone
who can help
if you're
willing to ask.
I'm Specs.
This is Tucker.
I'm Renai. Hi.
Hi.
You must be Josh.
Yeah. Hi.
That wasn't psychic.
Elise already told me
your name so...
Where is Elise?
She sent us
ahead to do some
preliminary tests.
Helps weed out
the nut jobs.
Hmm.
(BLOWS)
RENAI: What is that?
TUCKER: It's
a Trifield meter.
Measures DC fields
and the natural
electromagnetic environment.
Yeah. sometimes
old wiring can leak
into the atmosphere.
It causes hallucinations.
changes in energy.
It's a little more
important than that.
but whatever.
The tech stuff's
not really relevant
to you guys anyway.
It's all very
relevant. actually.
(MACHINE PULSING)
(STATIC)
(EXHALES)
(SPECS GASPS)
What?
Starfleet Series One.
It's hard to find.
Should have
kept it in its box.
This device measures
changes in UV light.
I make
all this equipment
myself. you know.
RENAI: It's impressive.
Thanks.
It's not that hard
if you know
what you're doing.
Yeah.
that one's basically
a modified toy.
I'm gonna need
some time alone
to concentrate.
(MACHINE PULSING)
(STATIC)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
This field is...
Look. the body is
made up of energy.
Where does
that energy go
when we die?
We can call Elise.
Now.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(LAUGHING)
I wasn't sure
the doorbell was
working. I'm sorry.
That's fine.
Come on in.
Thank you.
Mrs. Rainier?
No. Mrs. Rainier
is my mother.
Just call me Elise.
I'm Josh.
I knew that.
You've grown since
I last saw you.
Since you last saw me?
Mmm-hmm.
Your mother and I
have been friends
a long time.
Oh.
ELISE: Well. hello.
This is my wife. Renai.
How do you do?
Hi. thank you
for coming.
Thank you
for having me.
Can we get you
anything. Elise?
Oh. no. I'm fine.
thank you so much.
We took Trifield
and EMF readings
of the whole house.
all the wiring.
alarm clocks.
radios. toasters.
TV. record player.
fuse box.
nothing went
off the charts
except for the...
And the previous home?
Um. Tucker hadn't
monitored that yet.
You know what?
Don't even sweat it.
I'll make
myself available.
I'll get on that
this afternoon.
Yeah. but I'll have
to come. too.
because who's going
to operate the equipment?
Well. strictly.
I could do it without...
Yeah. but I need
to oversee...
Yeah. but it's not...
That's fine. gentlemen.
I don't think
bad wiring is
the problem here.
Um. may I walk
through the house?
RENAI: Sure. of course.
Thank you.
Your other children
are with Lorraine. right?
Yeah. they are.
Steven.
do you have
your sketchbook?
Yes. Yes. I do.
Good. 'Cause
we're gonna need it.
What do you
need that for?
Um. she tells me
what she sees.
and I draw it.
It's the most
important part
of her process.
That's debatable.
It's not debatable.
It is.
but whatever.
Leave the light off.
Hey. Dalton.
You are a very
handsome boy.
Your mom
and dad are here.
so don't you worry.
(CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
What? What?
ELISE: The face...
SPECS: What?
Blood red face.
Black...
Black arms.
Black legs.
Black body.
(SCRIBBLING)
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
Slow down.
His feet are black.
His legs are black.
Slow down.
What is it?
Oh. my God.
(CONTINUES WHISPERING)
And pitch black eyes.
They're like two dark holes.
He has hooves
for feet.
What?
And long
spidery fingernails.
Elise. what's...
Hey. what is that?
I'm not sure
if you're ready
to hear this yet.
but unfortunately.
I can't waste any time
easing you into it.
I want you to know.
this is what I believe.
and it may contradict
a previous medical
diagnosis. but...
You called me here.
and I'm taking that
as an acceptance
of my readings. Yes?
Yes. go on.
Your son
isn't in a coma.
Falling off a ladder
had nothing to do
with this.
His physical body's here.
But his
spiritual body is not.
And the reason
these disturbances.
they followed you
to a new home.
is because
it's not the house
that's haunted.
It's your son.
I don't understand.
(SIGHS)
Have you ever heard
of astral projection?
Yes. It's out of body
experience or something?
I like to
call them travelers.
You see.
these are people
with the ability
to leave their
physical body
and to travel
to different places
in astral form.
Now. Dalton.
he is a very accomplished
astral projector.
He's been
doing it in his sleep
for a long time.
He has been since
he was very young.
And he's unafraid
because he thinks
they're dreams.
And it's that
very lack of fear
that has led him
to travel too far.
And to become lost.
Lost?
Lost where?
In a place that
I call the Further.
What?
What does that mean?
The Further is a world
far beyond our own.
yet it's all around us.
a place
without time
as we know it.
It's a dark realm
filled with the tortured
souls of the dead.
a place not
meant for the living.
That's where Dalton is.
And the problem
is that with his
astral body gone.
he's just left us
with a physical body.
an empty vessel.
And there are
entities that know this
because they can smell it.
That's why they're
gathered around him.
Are these the things
that I've been seeing?
They're all trying
to get inside
of his physical body
simply because they...
They crave life.
the chance
to live again.
But there are
other entities
who are malevolent
and have a more
insidious agenda.
And then.
there's this.
A demon who
seeks Dalton's body
for one reason.
to cause
pain to others.
He is so desperate
to possess Dalton.
and he's the closest
of all the entities to
getting inside of him.
What do you mean
the closest?
Because these entities.
they can't just walk into
the bodies of the living
anytime they please.
To cross over
from their realm.
it takes time.
It takes energy.
But the longer that
Dalton's astral body
is kept away
from his physical body.
the weaker the link gets.
The easier it is
to possess him.
Is there
anything we can do
to bring Dalton back?
There's something
we could try.
It's a little unorthodox.
But I would need
your complete trust.
No. no. no. I'm sorry.
this has gone too far.
What? No. please. Josh.
You said you would
give her a chance.
I have given her
a chance. honey.
but I can't have
somebody coming
into our home
and telling us
that the reason
our son is in a coma
is because his soul
has floated off
somewhere
in another dimension.
We're gonna bring her
all the way here
and not even consider
what she's saying?
I did this to make sure
you could feel at ease.
And if it helped. great.
I've listened to
the dog and pony show.
I have seen the drawings.
But to bring
Dalton into it. no.
But why is our son
still in a coma?
Why can't
the doctors tell us
what is wrong with him?
How did the voice
of reason become
the bad guy here?
Don't you see. Renai?
You want to believe.
Anybody would.
You don't believe me!
I moved houses for you.
What do you mean.
I don't believe you?
I'm on your side here.
But this.
this is dangerous
and exploitative.
You guys come
into the home of
a seriously ill child.
and you make some
tenuous connection
between him
and the images my wife
is seeing. and voila!
Tears validate your power.
and thank you very much.
that will be $600 please.
Thank you for coming.
Please. Please.
Thank you.
No. I really understand.
Please.
Thank you for
your hospitality.
Good luck.
Oh. Jesus!
Sorry to waste your time.
JOSH: Where are you. buddy?
Did you go somewhere?
No.
No. you're right here.
You are right here.
Can you hear me?
I know you can hear me.
but you gotta show me.
okay. buddy?
You gotta show me
that you can hear me.
(SOBBING)
Okay.
What's most important
is that you realize
no two attempts
are the same.
I'm going to be
completely honest
with you about the results.
If there's no
dialogue established.
I'm gonna tell you.
TUCKER:  These
still cameras are rigged
to pick up any changes
in the atmosphere.
both electrical
or temperature-wise.
Don't be alarmed
if they go off.
ELISE:  You're gonna see
a lot of confusing things.
things you don't understand.
But do not question them
and do not speak in any way.
I want you to know
whatever I say
when I'm in tune
is going to be
at a very low volume.
You won't hear any of it.
But Steven's
gonna write it down.
He's going repeat it
for you. Okay?
Dim the lights. please.
(DALTON'S
HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
(WHISPERING)
We are calling
out to you. Dalton.
ELISE:  Tell us you're safe.
Tell us where you are.
Tell us you're safe.
Dalton.
Can you hear us?
Answer us.
ELISE:  Who's there?
Who's there?
Dalton. it's your
mother and father.
We've been
searching for you.
Where are you?
I can't see in here.
Dalton... Dalton.
you don't need to see.
Follow my voice.
Follow my voice. Dalton.
Dalton.
Why aren't you...
Why aren't you
talking anymore?
Dalton?
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
If they hear me.
they'll hurt me.
Who will hurt you?
Who will hurt you. Dalton?
The man
(HEART MONITOR
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
with
fire
on his face.
Dalton.
Dalton. can you
find your way out?
There is
no way out.
Follow my voice. Dalton.
Follow my voice.
Be quiet.
They'll hear you.
They won't
hear me. Dalton.
Follow my voice.
They heard you.
Oh. my God.
Mommy and Daddy.
Help. Help.
Help me. help me. help.
Dalton?
You bitch.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(HEART MONITOR
BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(HEART MONITOR FLAT LINING)
Dalton?
(GASPS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Specs!
(SCREAMING)
Leave this vessel!
Leave his body!
Tucker.
turn on the light!
Leave this body now!
Come here. Dalton.
Son. Come here.
He's alive.
He's alive. oh. God.
He's alive? Jesus.
Honey.
Oh. God.
TUCKER: Three cameras.
Around the clock.
We got nothing.
But I did find this
on the video.
Take a look.
You see that?
I went through it.
Frame by frame
by frame.
Oh. my God.
(DOOR BELL RINGS)
(SIGHS)
Who's that?
I'll get it.
Hi. Lorraine.
Mom. what are
you doing here?
ELISE: I asked your
mother to come over.
I called
her immediately
after the session.
Why?
There's something
we must talk about.
Lorraine.
have a seat.
Go on. Tell him.
Tell me what. Mom?
The reason
I knew to call
Elise in this situation.
the reason
I know her so well.
is because I called her
myself once. years ago.
to help you.
What are you
talking about. Mom?
It's no accident
that your son is
a gifted traveler.
The ability was
handed down to him.
By his father.
Me?
No. I don't do...
I can't do that.
When you were about eight.
you suffered night terrors.
these awful fits
of pure fear.
You were terrified
of an old woman
you said used to come
visit you at night.
I dismissed
your stories. I...
(SIGHS)
I told you to grow up.
And then
I saw her for myself.
At first.
I thought it was
a camera problem.
And then
I saw her again.
In each photo.
she got closer
and closer
and closer to you.
Finally.
I was so frightened.
I found Elise.
Do you remember
any of this.
honey. do you?
No. I... I don't.
Suppressing your memory
and your ability
to astral project
was the only
way to stop her
from getting into you.
But in the back
of your mind.
you're still afraid to
have your picture taken.
aren't you?
I kept those
photos hidden
from you ever since.
I advised Lorraine
to hide them.
to stop
taking your picture.
to just let you forget.
Who is she?
A parasite.
She befriended
your astral body
and then
drew you out
into the Further.
just as Dalton
has been drawn out.
I'm so sorry. Josh.
I didn't
want to make you
remember all this.
I do it
for the sake
of your son.
Your son is out there.
And you are
the only one that
can bring him back.
And with what
we saw tonight.
I would say
he doesn't have much
time left to wait for you.
Okay.
RENAI:  You've always
been stronger than me.
You can do this.
I love you.
Please come back.
ELISE: Remember
why you're traveling
and keep one foot
in this world.
Do not
draw attention
to yourself.
If they realize
you are not one of them.
they will come for
your physical body
in this world.
Ready?
Yeah.
I don't know what
I'm ready for.
but... Okay.
(TICKING)
Close your eyes. Josh.
take a deep breath.
and relax.
(EXHALES)
With each breath.
let the life
around you fade
into the background.
Just listen
to the ticking
of the metronome.
Focus on the spot
in the center
of your forehead.
The universe
is deathless.
It is deathless because
having no finite self.
it stays infinite.
A sound man.
by not advancing himself.
stays the further
ahead of himself.
It's useless.
I have no idea
what I'm doing.
(VOICE ECHOING)
Now you're outside.
Let my voice
be your guide.
Keep a steady stride.
Into the Further you go.
Dalton.
(EXHALES) He's in.
Dalton!
Hello?
Wait!
(WOMAN CRYING)
Hello?
(CRYING CONTINUES)
I'm looking
for my son Dalton.
(CHILD LAUGHING)
(WHISTLING)
(WHISTLING STOPS)
Dalton!
(GUN COCKING)
Where's my son?
Tell me
where my son is.
Please.
(GUN FIRING)
(CREAKING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(GRUNTING)
What's happening to him?
Jesus.
Help him. Elise!
Please!
You're stronger
than they are. Josh.
You can beat them.
You are stronger.
You are the one alive.
Get away from me!
(PANTING)
(CRYING)
Dalton!
Daddy?
Oh. God! Buddy!
Daddy!
Oh. my God! Oh. buddy.
Daddy.
Oh. my God.
Oh. buddy. it's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. Oh. God.
Daddy. look.
I'm chained.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Face me. buddy.
Face me. Come here.
We'll get you out.
buddy. okay?
Daddy's here.
What? What?
(TIPTOE THROUGH THE TULIPS
PLAYING)
♪ By the window.
that is where I'll be
♪ Come tiptoe
through the tulips with me
♪ Tiptoe from the garden
♪ By the garden
of the willow tree
♪ And tiptoe
through the tulips with me ♪
Oh. God. Okay.
It's okay.
Listen to me. Look at me.
None of this
is real. okay?
This is not real.
Look at me.
Look at my eyes. buddy.
None of this is real.
We're going to
go home. okay?
You gotta help me.
There's one.
Oh. my God. Dad.
He's looking.
(GRUNTS)
Come on. baby.
Stay here. baby.
Come on. stay with us.
Daddy!
(SNARLING)
He's made contact.
Grab the light!
He found your son.
I know it.
Well.
then wake them up.
for God sake!
I can't.
He needs to find us.
(PANTING)
I'm scared. Dad.
(GASPS)
No! Stop!
Please. Elise.
do something!
(BULBS SHATTERING)
Renai. you must
call out to him.
Josh. Josh.
Follow my voice!
Follow my voice. honey.
Get away! Get away!
Come back to us!
RENAI:  Follow my voice. Josh.
Daddy! Listen.
I think it's Mommy!
Josh.
come back to me.
Follow my voice.
Josh. follow my voice.
Follow my voice. Josh.
Follow my voice.
(SCRAPING)
There's something
in there! In there!
Elise!
Steven. Lorraine.
go check on Dalton.
SPECS: What?
Go check on Dalton.
What?
Go check on Dalton now!
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
(SPECS SCREAMING)
(BABY MONITOR EMITS STATIC)
(STATIC CONTINUES)
They're crossing over
into our world.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Elise!
ELISE: Tucker!
No. you have to shine
the light on Josh.
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
Let's go around back.
Shine the light
on Josh! On Josh!
Tucker. on Josh!
You've got
to call him back!
RENAI: Josh!
Josh! Josh! Come back
to us. Josh. please!
Josh! Josh!
Come back. please!
Come on. Dad!
Come on.
he's right behind us!
We have to go!
I'm right
behind you! Go!
You.
(SNARLING)
What do you
want from me?
I'm not scared of you.
I'm not scared
of you anymore.
You can get
away from me.
Get the hell
away from me!
Get away from me!
Leave me alone!
Please. please. please!
Come back to us!
Follow my voice!
Please. honey!
Josh. come back!
Come back to us!
Get the hell
away from me!
Please. Josh. please.
come back to us. please!
Follow my voice!
Follow my voice! Please!
Josh. please!
Come back. please!
Leave me alone!
(GASPING)
I've got Dalton.
He's awake!
Oh. my boy!
He's okay! He's okay!
JOSH: We did it. buddy.
You're back. You're back.
Dude. I got some
amazing shots.
You're gonna
write a book.
and my photos
are gonna be the
main selling point.
Not the main
selling point.
but they'll
definitely be important.
They will be important.
A picture's worth
a thousand words.
Yeah.
but words are worth
a thousand words. too.
You're really hungry.
aren't you?
And I'm tired. too.
You're tired?
No. you can't be tired.
Yes. I can.
No. you've been asleep
for far too long.
And you know what?
I'm never letting you
go to sleep again.
You showed me a new world.
No. I didn't.
You've been there
before. remember?
Well. let's hope
I forget again.
Guess I don't need
these anymore.
What?
Nothing.
I'm gonna
get rid of these.
All right. (SIGHS)
Why did you do that?
Why would you do that
to me when you know
how I feel about that?
Why? Why?
Why? Why? Why?
No. you're not tired.
In fact. you're never
going to sleep again.
You have to stay awake
for the rest of
your life. with me.
No.
(CHOKING)
Why? Why? Why?
(JOSH YELLING)
You bitch!
Can you watch him.
Lorraine?
Sure.
Elise.
(GASPS)
Josh! Josh!
Josh. where are you?
Josh!
Honey. please! Josh!
Josh?
Oh. Jesus.
JOSH: Renai.
I'm right here.
(GASPS)